<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: codeacademy | Adamin]]></title>
  <link href="http://pensive612.github.com/blog/categories/codeacademy/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://pensive612.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2013-01-22T16:30:18-08:00</updated>
  <id>http://pensive612.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Adamin]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[github@adamin.net]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Its Time To Get Real Up In Here, Parse.]]></title>
    <link href="http://pensive612.github.com/blog/2013/01/22/real-up-in-here-parse/"/>
    <updated>2013-01-22T11:29:00-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://pensive612.github.com/blog/2013/01/22/real-up-in-here-parse</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class="personal" markdown='1'>
<p>Oh man.  This article was supposed to be called Querying Objects in Parse.  But it looks like
it might be time for a little intervention instead.</p>

<p>Parse....CodeAcademy....  Its me.  Your friend Adam.</p>

<p>I like what I like.  And guess what.  I like you guys.</p>

<p>You've given me invaluable education and services.  And haven't asked for anything in return.</p>

<p>And its hard to say this, but at least you're going to hear it from a friend.</p>

</div>


<!-- more -->


<hr />

<p>Your Parse lesson in the <a href="http://www.codecademy.com/tracks/apis">Learning APIs</a>
course is so buggy, that I'm worried you are actually going to <strong>detract</strong> new and valuable developers
to your otherwise, incredible service.</p>

<p>To pass a step I have to wander through text, removing spaces, adding them back.  Cutting text, adding it back.</p>

<p>Submit.  Run Code.  Submit.  Delete.  Edit.  Read the docs.  Submit again.</p>

<p>All this, and my code was correct the first time.</p>

<p><img src="http://puu.sh/1QSsH"></p>

<hr />

<h3>Here's where things are going wrong</h3>

<ul>
<li>The coderunner is crazy buggy.</li>
<li>The content descriptions for each step are very incomplete, and inconsistent.</li>
<li>You're the only API I've seen so far in these courses that requires an actual signup (you might want to explain why that is)</li>
<li>Hints are non-existent or copy/pasted from previous paragraphs.</li>
<li>You RARELY get an error message, and if you do, it is usually not the correct one.</li>
<li>I've spent no more than 10% of my time in this course actually writing.  And about 10x longer than I spent in the other courses.</li>
</ul>


<h3>This is my honest advice.</h3>

<p>Pull the course until you guys can fix things.  You are souring your own name and reputation
to any new user who is intrigued and putting in the time to learn the API.</p>

<p>You guys should have the best course on here.  The first two courses, <a href="http://www.codecademy.com/tracks/youtube">YouTube</a> and <a href="http://www.codecademy.com/tracks/soundcloud">SoundCloud</a> were seamless.  Piece of cake.</p>

<p>I know you guys can come up with something awesome.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Basic Objects in Parse]]></title>
    <link href="http://pensive612.github.com/blog/2013/01/21/basic-objects-in-parse/"/>
    <updated>2013-01-21T17:03:00-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://pensive612.github.com/blog/2013/01/21/basic-objects-in-parse</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Creating an object in <a href="https://parse.com/">Parse</a> is the foundation of the API.</p>

<p>Without it.  You really don't have anything.  Not even this blog post.</p>

<p>Here's the important steps as I've seen them so far:</p>

<p><code>javascript
// Extend the Parse.Object
var Character = Parse.Object.extend("Character");
</code></p>

<!-- more -->


<p><em>Keep in mind that Classes get CapitalCase.
And instances will get snakeCase</em>.  It helps to be able to decipher variable types at a quick glance.</p>

<p><code>javascript
// Create a new instance of the object
var character = new Character();
</code></p>

<p>Now its time to set/get some keys on the object</p>

<p><code>javascript
// Setting a key/value on the instance
character.set('name', 'nelson');
</code></p>

<p>And I'm sure you know it doesn't mean a thing til you save that thing.
<code>javascript
// Save it to the database
character.save();
</code></p>

<p>Still frustrating that I'm dealing with bugs in the CodeAcademy/Parse tutorial app.
As well as inconsistencies in the text.</p>

<p>I've now created my object.  I'm fairly certain its correct.  But can't get the code
to run.  And have no idea if its my code or the checker.</p>

<p>This is what I have:</p>

<p>``` javascript
// extend the subClass
var Post = Parse.Object.extend("Post");</p>

<p>// create instances of the subClass
var post = new Post();
var post2 = new Post();</p>

<p>// set and save the objects
post.set('text', 'got some text in here');
post.save();</p>

<p>post2.set('text', 'look at me, saving text');
post2.save();
```</p>

<p>Argh.  Might have to skip over the Parse tutorial for now and come back to it.</p>

<p>Oh wait!  After waiting long enough to type this entry out.  I'm now allowed to
test my code.  That i know is correct.</p>

<p><img src="http://puu.sh/1QSsH"></p>

<p>Oops try again.
Wait, 'like' key?  That's not even in this step.</p>

<p>Bah.</p>

<p>Hint repeating the exact same text above it?</p>

<p><img src="http://puu.sh/1QSx6"></p>

<p>Bah.</p>

<p>Looks like I picked the wrong week to quit sniffing glue.</p>

<p>Another time then...</p>

<h4>Wait!</h4>

<p>Hoozah!  The coderunner has finally decided it will give my exact same code another
chance.  And guess what!  It works!</p>

<p>Woot woot.</p>

<p>Hmm.  maybe this is some new alternative learning method.  Make you read your code a hundred
times.  Make you read the docs a hundred times.  Get frustrated.  yell, research.</p>

<p>And just when its realy sunk in.  BAM!  That very same original code is now acceptable.</p>

<p>Very alternative... Kudos Parse and CodeAcademy.  Kudos.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Initializing Parse]]></title>
    <link href="http://pensive612.github.com/blog/2013/01/21/initializing-parse/"/>
    <updated>2013-01-21T16:30:00-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://pensive612.github.com/blog/2013/01/21/initializing-parse</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img class="right" src="http://puu.sh/1QRgk"></p>

<p>Okay, picking up off the last section where I talked about my experience with starting
the Parse Lesson on CodeAcademy.</p>

<p>I now have my Parse account and have been instructed to create an app and use my credentials in the app.</p>

<p>Easy enough.  I just clicked on the dropdown, created my app and pressed the copy buttons
to get my strings.  Now time to initialize Parse with my credentials.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>The next part is super easy.  Just calling the initialize method on the Parse object.
Pass 2 parameters.  Both your <em>application_id</em> and <em>javscript_key</em>.</p>

<p>``` javascript
// Initializing
Parse.initialize("application_id", "javascript_key");</p>

<p>```</p>

<p>Here's a cool trick, If you have a wide screen, and you maximize it, the result window
will go next to the script window.  Makes it easier to Run the code.</p>

<p><img src="http://puu.sh/1QRvh"></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Parse on CodeAcademy]]></title>
    <link href="http://pensive612.github.com/blog/2013/01/21/parse-on-codeacademy/"/>
    <updated>2013-01-21T16:10:00-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://pensive612.github.com/blog/2013/01/21/parse-on-codeacademy</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>So this is awesome.  Really awesome.</p>

<p><a href="http://www.codecademy.com/">CodeAcademy</a> has gone out and created an <a href="http://www.codecademy.com/tracks/apis">API course</a>.</p>

<p>I think its going to do really well.  And they were very clever to get big companies
with useful APIs to join in and write mini lessons to use their own APIs.</p>

<p>And what more could I ask for.  <a href="https://parse.com/">Parse</a> is in there.</p>

<p><img src="http://puu.sh/1QR2M"></p>

<p>Here's the honest feedback so far.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>I've been doing them in order.  Starting with the general HTTP lesson.  Straight forward
nice.  Made me feel like I have a chance and grasping all this.</p>

<p>Then doing them in order, I got to the YouTube lesson.  Very cool.  They did a good job of
making the Google API not feel intimidating.  And I was able to fly through it pretty quickly.</p>

<p>Second was <a href="https://soundcloud.com/">SoundCloud</a>.  I think this is a really cool project, and I love how they give it all to you in an API.
Promptly got through creating a player, an interface to upload recordings, and view comments in real time.  Awesome.</p>

<p>And here we are Parse.</p>

<p>Ready to get into it.</p>

<h4>First impression?</h4>

<p>Well.  it looks like they're the first of the lessons that I've encountered that is
using their own interface inside the Results window.  Could be cool?!</p>

<p>Wah, wah.  Its super buggy.  And looking at the forums.  People are reporting the same
thing.  I hate that the first chapter has taken me longer than almost any other entire section.</p>

<p>But I have faith that they will fix this.  And when they do.  I'll jump back and edit this.</p>

<p>What they're trying to do is quite complex.  And CodeAcademy is prone to bugs.  So I'll chalk
this up as 'working out the kinks'.</p>

<h4>Okay, I've gotten past the first section.  Hopefully things clear up on the second.</h4>

<p>Doh.  Its the first API lesson that requires you to go and create an account.</p>

<p>I'm guessing the fact that their API is writing data is why they chose not to make a test API key.</p>

<p>Obviously it will probably get them some signups as well.  But it did take actual setup unlike any of the others.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Playing With Parse]]></title>
    <link href="http://pensive612.github.com/blog/2013/01/20/playing-with-parse/"/>
    <updated>2013-01-20T21:53:00-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://pensive612.github.com/blog/2013/01/20/playing-with-parse</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>One of the companies I've been really interested in lately is
<a href="http://www.parse.com">Parse</a>.</p>

<p>I love what they do and how they approach it.  And especially how fast it seems they iterate.</p>

<p>It's inspiring.  And one day, I'd love to work for a company like that.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>I'm going to try and do a series on my <a href="/blog/categories/parse/">learnings with Parse</a> mostly because:</p>

<ul>
<li>I was inspired by this position: <a href="https://parse.com/jobs#devevang">Parse Developer Evangelist</a></li>
<li>Writing about my learning will help improve it</li>
<li>Something I learn here might help you on your path</li>
<li>The idea of separating the front-end and your own data API is pretty exciting</li>
</ul>


<p>And I also think it will be helpful to companies like Parse, to see first hand what a hungry
and budding developer goes through when trying to understand their services.</p>

<p>If you guys have any questions, let me know.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
